<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name = "fragility">Fragility</string>
    <string name = "fragilityDesc">This spell alters the solidity of an object, reducing its sturdiness and making it easy to break. Anything affected automatically loses its Damage Barrier; if the spell is cast on arms or armor, their Fortitude receives a reduction of -2. This spell affects objects with a Presence of no more than 30.</string>
    <string name = "fragilityEff">+5 to the maximum Presence that can be affected and -1 to Fortitude</string>

    <string name = "dismantle">Dismantle</string>
    <string name = "dismantleDesc">Dismantles an object made of various pieces. It affects inanimate objects with a Presence of no more than 20.</string>
    <string name = "dismantleEff">+5 to the maximum Presence that can be affected</string>

    <string name = "destroyIntense">Destroy Intensities</string>
    <string name = "destroyIntenseDesc">Destroys one intensity of one of the three types of existing energies (Cold, Fire, or Electricity).</string>
    <string name = "destroyIntenseEff">-1 additional Intensity</string>

    <string name = "minorDestruct">Minor Destruction</string>
    <string name = "minorDestructDesc">Affects the essence of a lifeless material object, destroying it completely, as long as its Presence is no greater than 20.</string>
    <string name = "minorDestructEff">+5 to the maximum Presence that can be affected</string>

    <string name = "destructSphere">Sphere of Destruction</string>
    <string name = "destructSphereDesc">Projects a ball of magical energy. Sphere of Destruction is an Energy Attack Type with a Base Damage of 30.</string>
    <string name = "destructSphereEff">+5 to Base Damage</string>

    <string name = "weakIncrease">Increase Weakness</string>
    <string name = "weakIncreaseDesc">This spell finds a being\'s weak points, and makes them weaker supernaturally. In game terms, it doubles the penalty the individual suffers for any vulnerability. For example, an elemental who is especially vulnerable to light would suffer quadruple damage, instead of double damage, from an attack using light, while a character vulnerable to poisons would have his VR reduced to a fourth of its usual value. To avoid being affected by Increase Weakness, its target needs to pass a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120. If he fails, he can only roll the Check again when he is affected by his weakness.</string>
    <string name = "weakIncreaseEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "magDestruct">Magic Destruction</string>
    <string name = "magDestructDesc">Destroys a spell whose Zeon value is no greater than 40. Since Magic Destruction is passive, it can be employed to nullify any spell launched in the same combat turn.</string>
    <string name = "magDestructEff">+5 to the Zeon value of the spell</string>

    <string name = "aggravateDamage">Aggravate Damage</string>
    <string name = "aggravateDamageDesc">Increases the Base Damage of any attack (physical or supernatural) by 30 points. For example, if an attacker is wielding a weapon with a Base Damage of 60, using the spell increases it to 90. In spite of its being a passive spell, it must be cast before any dice are rolled, to make it possible to calculate the opponent\'s respective attack and defense factors.</string>
    <string name = "aggravateDamageEff">+5 damage</string>

    <string name = "matrixDestruction">Destruction of Matrices</string>
    <string name = "matrixDestructionDesc">This spell unravels the energy matrices of a Psychic Power whose Potential is no more than 80 (that is to say, of Medium Difficulty). Since it is a passive spell, it can be employed to nullify any Psychic Power launched in the same combat turn.</string>
    <string name = "matrixDestructionEff">+10 to the Psychic Potential of the power that can be affected</string>

    <string name = "wound">Wound</string>
    <string name = "woundDesc">Wound affects the physical condition of an individual, doing damage to his health. It produces wounds and damage equal to 20% of his current Life Points, not of his total. Resisting this spell requires beating a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120.</string>
    <string name = "woundEff">-5% of Life Points and +5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "kiDestroy">Destroy Ki</string>
    <string name = "kiDestroyDesc">The magic unleashed by this spell penetrates the soul of its victim, dissolving his reserve of Ki. The victim must beat a MR Check with a difficulty of 120, or he loses as many points of Ki as the level of Failure. The caster chooses the order and distribution of points lost among the different characteristics.</string>
    <string name = "kiDestroyEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "produceDamage">Produce Damage</string>
    <string name = "produceDamageDesc">Through the use of this spell, the caster automatically causes a wound in an individual\'s body. If the victim does not beat an MR Check with a Difficulty of 120, he suffers 40 points of direct damage. Creatures with Damage Resistance multiply the damage by their Resistance multiple.</string>
    <string name = "produceDamageEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty and +10 to the damage received</string>

    <string name = "senseDestruct">Destruction of Senses</string>
    <string name = "senseDestructDesc">The caster cuts off the senses of the individual who fails a MR Check with a Difficulty of 100. The caster can choose which senses to take.</string>
    <string name = "senseDestructEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "mysticBolt">Mystic Bolt</string>
    <string name = "mysticBoltDesc">Projects a mystical bolt that affects a single target. The attack is an Energy Attack Type with a Base Damage of 100.</string>
    <string name = "mysticBoltEff">+5 to Base Damage</string>

    <string name = "tieUnravel">Unravel Ties</string>
    <string name = "tieUnravelDesc">Using this spell, the caster undoes any type of tie that permits a summoner to Control his creatures. It can be used with equal effect on either the controller or the controlled creature, but it is always the creator of the Bound whose MR is checked. If cast upon the creature, it affects only the ties binding the two of them, but if it is cast directly against the summoner, it breaks an additional binding for every 10 points by which the controller fails a MR with a Difficulty of 120.</string>
    <string name = "tieUnravelEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "resistDestroy">Destroy Resistances</string>
    <string name = "resistDestroyDesc">The person affected by this spell has all his Resistances reduced by an amount equal to the margin by which he did not pass an MR Check with a Difficulty of 120.</string>
    <string name = "resistDestroyEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "undoState">Undo States</string>
    <string name = "undoStateDesc">Immediately undoes any of the States described in Chapter 14, or others that are equivalent to them. This spell can affect as many targets as desired as long as their accumulated Presence is no higher than 120. The spell cannot undo the penalties to action caused by a Critical. Resisting the spell requires beating a MR Check with a Difficulty of 100.</string>
    <string name = "undoStateEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty and +10 to the maximum Presence that can be affected</string>

    <string name = "destructDome">Dome of Destruction</string>
    <string name = "destructDomeDesc">Unleashes a dome of supernatural energy that bursts over an area of 10 meters in radius. It is not possible to choose targets within the area. The attack is an Energy Attack Type with a Base Damage of 80.</string>
    <string name = "destructDomeEff">+5 Base Damage and +5 meters to radius</string>

    <string name = "decayZone">Zone of Decay</string>
    <string name = "decayZoneDesc">This spell covers a fixed area of 10 meters in radius, within which all forms of life begin to rot and decay at an accelerated pace. Anyone found within the Zone of Decay loses 10% of their total Life Points unless they beat a MR Check with a Difficulty of 100. Each turn they remain within the Zone, they must make a new check, regardless of whether they passed a previous check or not. The condition for being affected is simply being within the area.</string>
    <string name = "decayZoneEff">+5 meters to radius and +5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "destructAura">Aura of Destruction</string>
    <string name = "destructAuraDesc">Enchants a place or object, creating in the area an aura of magic that destroys everything that comes into contact with it. Anyone who touches it must beat a MR Check with a Difficulty of 80, or he loses as many points of Life Points equivalent to the Failure level. The maximum Presence of the object or place affected is 60. However, even if the object is very large, the aura cannot extend more than 1 meter long. The spell can affect even its caster.</string>
    <string name = "destructAuraEff">+5 to Presence, +1 meter, and +5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "destroyMem">Destroy Memories</string>
    <string name = "destroyMemDesc">Affects the memories of an individual, making him forget whatever the caster wishes. The spell does not affect a person\'s abilities, only their conscious memories. The MR or PsR to avoid the effects is 100.</string>
    <string name = "destroyMemEff">+5 to the MR or PsR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "learnBlock">Block Learning</string>
    <string name = "learnBlockDesc">This spell impedes the ability of an individual to learn, completely preventing him from developing or acquiring new knowledge. While a person is under the effects of this spell, he cannot acquire new Experience Points or develop any abilities or powers. To avoid the effects of the spell, he must beat a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120. It is only possible to repeat the Resistance check once per day.</string>
    <string name = "learnBlockEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "forbid">Forbid</string>
    <string name = "forbidDesc">The caster vetoes some specific action by the spell\'s victim, completely prohibiting him from even attempting to do it. The spell Forbids only Active Actions. Resisting the spell requires beating a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120. If the forbidden action is very general, like attack or move, the target can add a special bonus to his MR between +10 and +30.</string>
    <string name = "forbidEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "powerDestroy">Destroy Powers</string>
    <string name = "powerDestroyDesc">The person affected by this spell is completely unable to use any of his supernatural powers. He is thereby prevented from using any magical, psychic, or Ki powers he possesses. Mystical beings also lose all their powers (although not their natural abilities). To avoid the effects of the spell, its target must beat a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120.</string>
    <string name = "powerDestroyEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "greatMysticBolt">Greater Mystic Bolt</string>
    <string name = "greatMysticBoltDesc">Projects a powerful supernatural bolt. The attack is an Energy Attack Type with a Base Damage of 150.</string>
    <string name = "greatMysticBoltEff">+10 to Base Damage</string>

    <string name = "destroyWill">Destroy Will</string>
    <string name = "destroyWillDesc">This spell affects a 10-meter radius area, within which any individual who does not beat a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120 automatically loses the ability to make decisions. While a person is influenced by this spell, he cannot undertake any Active Action, even moving, except in case of necessity.</string>
    <string name = "destroyWillEff">+5 meters to radius and +5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "weakZone">Zone of Weakness</string>
    <string name = "weakZoneDesc">With this spell, the caster weakens the fiber of reality itself within a given area, making everything inside become fragile and vulnerable. Any damage produced within the spell\'s area is automatically doubled, and characters suffer Criticals as though their entire body was a vulnerable point. Structures and constructions automatically lose their Damage Barrier, and objects with a Fortitude rating such as swords and armor suffer a -5 penalty. The spell affects an area with a radius of 20 meters, which remains stationary where it was cast. Any living being can avoid the spell\'s effects by beating a MR Check with a Difficulty of 140. The condition for being affected by the Zone of Weakness is simply to be within its area, and it is only possible to free oneself by leaving it, since it is only permitted to repeat the Resistance Check once per day.</string>
    <string name = "weakZoneEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty and +10 meters</string>

    <string name = "essenceDestruct">Essence of Destruction</string>
    <string name = "essenceDestructDesc">The caster alters the material of a body, transforming it to a form of purely destructive energy capable of devouring everything it comes into contact with. While in this state, the body can only be damaged by attacks capable of affecting supernatural targets, and anyone coming in contact with it must beat a MR Check with a Difficulty of 80, or lose as many Life Points as the Failure Level. The maximum Presence that can be affected is 100.</string>
    <string name = "essenceDestructEff">+5 to the maximum Presence affected</string>

    <string name = "death">Death</string>
    <string name = "deathDesc">The caster is capable of producing the death of a living being by separating his soul from his body. The power of this spell is so great that it can even kill spiritual beings or necromantic creatures, converting them to simple dead souls or even destroying them completely. To resist the effects of this terrible spell, it is necessary to beat a MR or PhR Check with a Difficulty of 120.</string>
    <string name = "deathEff">+5 to the MR or PhR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "devourZone">Devouring Zone</string>
    <string name = "devourZoneDesc">Like a deadly vortex, the Devouring Zone spreads, shredding the essence of everything it finds in its path by slowly consuming it. Little by little, the things this spell reaches weaken until they are unmade, whether they are material objects or living beings. Every day the victims (either people or things) remain within its area, they must beat a MR or PhR of 140, or temporarily have their Base Presence reduced by five points. If their Presence falls to zero, they decompose leaving little trace. Living beings also receive an additional All Action Penalty equivalent to twice the Presence Points lost. The spiritual damage is recouped at a rate of five points per day once the person leaves the area of the spell. Devouring Zone affects an area with a radius of 500 meters, which remains stationary where it was cast.</string>
    <string name = "devourZoneEff">+500 meters to radius and +5 to the MR or PhR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "destroyCapabilities">Destroy Capabilities</string>
    <string name = "destroyCapabilitiesDesc">This spell destroys part of the abilities or powers of an individual, stripping him of them forever. The caster freely removes 50 DP from the affected person, choosing the capacities or fields affected. He could, for instance, cut the person\'s Attack Ability by 30 DP and take the remaining DP from a Secondary Ability he chooses. It is also possible to destroy the Supernatural Powers of mystical creatures with this spell, using the value of DP listed in Chapter 26 for reference. Destroy Capabilities also permits one to strip advantages chosen with Creation Points, at a cost of 100 DP per CP. The MR Difficulty to avoid the effects is 120.</string>
    <string name = "destroyCapabilitiesEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty and -10 DP</string>

    <string name = "existSever">Sever Existence</string>
    <string name = "existSeverDesc">As though wielding a knife of nothingness, the caster can cut through reality itself, annihilating anything in his path. Anything that comes in contact with the spell is destroyed physically and spiritually, leaving no sign that it ever existed. The spell permits either cutting a line 10 meters long or focusing all its power in a single point, destroying everything it touches completely unless the required Resistance Check is successful. In spite of being a Spiritual spell, the cut in reality is perfectly visible even to those incapable of seeing magic. The objects or individuals cut off by Sever Existence are destroyed completely, and do not return to the Flow of Souls. The MR Difficulty to resist the effects of the spell is 120, but if focused on a single point, becomes 140.</string>
    <string name = "existSeverEff">+10 meters to the line and +5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "destructRain">Rain of Destruction</string>
    <string name = "destructRainDesc">This spell unleashes a storm of selective blasts that destroy only the targets designated by the caster within a 50-meter radius. It has a Base Damage of 200, and attacks on Energy AT. Additionally, if it impacts a target and causes damage to him, the victim must beat a MR Check with a Difficulty of 140, or he loses a quantity of Life Points equal to the Margin of Failure.</string>
    <string name = "destructRainEff">+10 meters to radius, +5 to Base Damage, and +5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "destructZeon">Destruction of Zeon</string>
    <string name = "destructZeonDesc">By directly affecting the essence of magic, this spell is capable of dissipating the power of another active spell, automatically diminishing its Zeon value by 60 points. If the diminished spell is thereby reduced below its base cost, it disappears.</string>
    <string name = "destructZeonEff">-5 to the Zeon of the spell</string>

    <string name = "heavenSweep">Sweep from the Heavens</string>
    <string name = "heavenSweepDesc">By stealing away its very essence, this spell takes away the divine presence of an entity, temporarily transforming it into an earthly creature. In terms of the rules of the game, the creature affected by the spell has its Gnosis value reduced by 10. That reduction affects the powers or abilities of the entity that depend on Gnosis, and so it cannot use them while in the reduced state. Resisting the spell requires beating a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120. It is not possible to repeat the Resistance Check while it remains active.</string>
    <string name = "heavenSweepEff">-5 to the Gnosis and +5 to the MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "voidSpell">Void</string>
    <string name = "voidDesc">This spell forms a sphere of absolute void that absorbs into itself all physical and spiritual matter around it, unmaking them completely. The dome has a 5-meter radius and must be located in an open space. Once cast, it remains fixed in that location until the spell ends. Once created, it begins to suck in anything within a 50-meter radius. The power of attraction of the spell employs an equivalent Strength of 14, and anyone failing in an Opposed Check of characteristics will be drawn toward it at a rate of 10 meters for every point of difference. The void is so powerful that anything coming into contact with the sphere weakens until it disappears. Each combat turn a victim remains within the dome, he must beat two distinct Resistance Checks with a Difficulty of 120; one is a MR Check which if failed causes him to lose a number of Zeon equivalent to the margin of failure, and the other is a PhR Check, which if failed causes him to lose as many points of Life Points as the Margin of Failure. When a victim has lost all Zeon, he begins to permanently lose one point of Power for every 100 points of Zeon he would continue to lose. If his Power falls to zero, or he dies from loss of Life Points, his being is totally swallowed by the nothingness. Although the caster is not drawn by the attractive power of the dome, he will suffer the effects of the Void if he comes in contact with its nucleus.</string>
    <string name = "voidEff">+1 meter to radius, +50 meters to the area of influence, and +5 to the MR and PhR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "greatDestruction">Greater Destruction</string>
    <string name = "greatDestructionDesc">Provides the ability to destroy part of the material world on a grand scale, disintegrating even large constructions such as entire cities or vast areas of land. This spell can affect as many inorganic objects as desired as long as the sum of their Presence is no higher than 100.</string>
    <string name = "greatDestructionEff">+10 to the maximum Presence that can be affected</string>

    <string name = "soulDestroy">Destroy Souls</string>
    <string name = "soulDestroyDesc">The power unleashed by Destroy Souls sweeps away the spiritual matter around the caster, ending the existence of anyone who does not resist its effects. Any individual within an area of 5 kilometers from the point where the spell is unleashed by the caster must make a MR Check against a Difficulty of 100 or have his soul completely disintegrated causing immediate death.</string>
    <string name = "soulDestroyEff">+5 kilometer radius and +5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "chaos">Chaos</string>
    <string name = "chaosDesc">Chaos is a spell of almost insuperable power, since it is capable of shaking the very pillars of reality. Upon being unleashed, the caster causes the order of things to crumble, altering the balance of all things in a completely unexpected way. Inside the zone of Chaos, nothing works as it should, and all events are unnaturally twisted. For example, chaos can affect gravity, making some things as light as feathers and others as heavy as lead. It can affect the weather, causing icy winds only yards from tropical gales or heat waves. This spell does not affect only the natural elements, though. It can influence the feelings and instincts of living beings, making lovers hate each other with a passion, or irreconcilable enemies form bonds of peace. The spell can even affect the passage of time, making it flow more quickly or slowly (it cannot be used to travel to the past, however). That is to say, Chaos is capable of affecting practically any imaginable facet of reality.\nThe caster can designate a specific aspect of reality he wishes to alter, or on the other hand, transform it completely. In either case, this spell does not give the caster direct control over what is changing, so the results and consequences of events can be, as the name of the spell implies, completely chaotic.\nChaos covers a maximum radius of 100 kilometers, and is static in the place it was cast. It automatically affects anyone with a Gnosis of 15 or less.</string>
    <string name = "chaosEff">+100 kilometers to radius and +1 to the Gnosis that can be affected</string>

    <string name = "uncreation">Uncreation</string>
    <string name = "uncreationDesc">This spell permits the caster to designate an aspect of existence, one as far-reaching as a city or race, or as precise as a single specific individual, and simply make it so it ceases to exist. The unmade item or person is erased from reality with all the consequences that implies, so that it never did exist. No one who knew of what was unmade remembers it, and all events it may have affected are modified as though what was unmade had no part in it; even returning to life those whose death the unmade might have caused (as long as their souls were not destroyed). Only entities with a Gnosis of more than 40 will be conscious of what happened. It is only possible to make one MR Check against a Difficulty of 140 to avoid the effects of this spell, even if it affects a multitude of persons or objects. The MR Check is made using the highest resistance that anyone or anything to be affected by Uncreation has at that exact moment. It is not possible to unmake elements of the past, only things that are currently present.</string>
    <string name = "uncreationEff">+5 to the MR Difficulty</string>
</resources>