<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name = "detectMinerals">Detect Minerals</string>
    <string name = "detectMineralsDesc">The caster can detect a particular mineral\'s location in a 10-meter radius. The spell also gives an approximation of the size and purity of the source. Energy-based barriers can not be overcome.</string>
    <string name = "detectMineralsEff">+5 meters to radius</string>

    <string name = "controlMineral">Mineral Control</string>
    <string name = "controlMineralDesc">This spell enables the caster to move, reshape, and control any mineral substance with a Presence of 30 or lower. However, the caster cannot endow a mineral with capacities it does not already possess. In other words, the caster may reshape a pebble into an arrowhead, but he could not make it inflict Electrical damage. Some golems and stone elementals can be controlled with this spell. Mineral-based creatures may avoid the effect of this spell by passing a MR Check with a Difficulty of 100. The control check must be repeated immediately if the creature is given an order completely opposed to its nature.</string>
    <string name = "controlMineralEff">+10 to the maximum Presence affected and +5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "weightIncrement">Weight Increment</string>
    <string name = "weightIncrementDesc">This spell increases a physical body\'s weight by 20 kg.</string>
    <string name = "weightIncrementEff">+10 kg</string>

    <string name = "transMineral">Transform Mineral</string>
    <string name = "transMineralDesc">This spell changes one type of material into another, modifying its natural composition. It can affect rocks and metals with a base Presence not higher than 30. For instance, it can turn a piece of limestone into a gold nugget. It can transform up to 10 kilograms of material.</string>
    <string name = "transMineralEff">+5 to the maximum Presence affected and +10 kilograms</string>

    <string name = "firmness">Firmness</string>
    <string name = "firmnessDesc">This spell enhances the endurance of individuals or objects, making them more resistant to damage. When cast upon a living organism, it grants a +20 bonus to any PhR Check to avoid the effects of a Critical. On the other hand, when applied to an object with Fortitude, it increases it by +2. Each Firmness spell can affect only one body or object at a time.</string>
    <string name = "firmnessEff">+5 to PhR or +1 to Fortitude</string>

    <string name = "stoneBarrier">Stone Barrier</string>
    <string name = "stoneBarrierDesc">This spell raises a material barrier allowing the spellcaster to repel any damaging attacks including those based on Energy. However, this shield is unable to stop Spiritual effects that only call for MR or PsR. The spell can take up to 600 points before being broken, but it has a Damage Barrier of 60 against physical attacks.</string>
    <string name = "stoneBarrierEff">+100 Resistance Points and +5 to Damage Barrier</string>

    <string name = "slowness">Slowness</string>
    <string name = "slownessDesc">This spell decreases motion and reaction speed of the selected individual. If the affected character does not pass a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120, his Initiative decreases by 50 points and a -2 penalty is applied to his Movement Value.</string>
    <string name = "slownessEff">+5 to MR Difficulty, -5 to Initiative and -1 to Movement Value</string>

    <string name = "shell">Shell</string>
    <string name = "shellDesc">This spell creates a physical shell with an AT 2 against all kinds of attacks, except Energy-based attacks. Even though it is considered armor, no penalties are applied to the turn Initiative for using extra protection layers.</string>
    <string name = "shellEff">+1 to AT</string>

    <string name = "magnetShield">Magnetic Shield</string>
    <string name = "magnetShieldDesc">By controlling magnetic fields around him, the spellcaster raises a shield with the ability of repelling any attack of a metallic nature made against him, including bullets, arrows, and darts with metal tips. The shield\'s magnetism causes a distortion that results in a -50 penalty to the attacker\'s offensive ability. The shield will take up to 300 damage points before being broken, but it will only be affected by Energy-damaging attacks. This barrier is virtually useless against immaterial or Spiritual attacks.</string>
    <string name = "magnetShieldEff">+100 Resistance points</string>

    <string name = "passMatter">Pass Through Solid Matter</string>
    <string name = "passMatterDesc">This spell enables one or more subjects, as appointed by the spellcaster, to pass through solid objects. The recipients of the spell do not exactly become immaterial, as they are still affected by heat or cold, but they can completely ignore all things non-Energy based. In this way, characters can decide to pass through anything from walls to sword blades as if they did not exist. It is possible for the caster to determine what materials can be passed through and which cannot. The maximum total Presences that can be affected may not exceed 100.</string>
    <string name = "passMatterEff">+10 to the maximum Presence</string>

    <string name = "earthSpike">Earth Spike</string>
    <string name = "earthSpikeDesc">Giant stone spikes erupt from the ground and impale targets on the surface. The spell allows for a maximum of two spikes, each with a 60 point Base Damage in the Thrust Attack Type; they cannot affect immaterial beings, or those only damaged by Energy, unless Earth Spike is combined with an Enchant spell. Each spike may be used to attack the same, or different targets. This spell cannot be employed to perform a spell clash.</string>
    <string name = "earthSpikeEff">One additional spike</string>

    <string name = "breakage">Breakage</string>
    <string name = "breakageDesc">This magically increases a targeted object\'s or weapon\'s breakage by four points.</string>
    <string name = "breakageEff">+1 to the object\'s Breakage</string>

    <string name = "telemetry">Telemetry</string>
    <string name = "telemetryDesc">This spell allows the caster to read the story of an object or person he comes into contact with, including the most important events in which it has been involved during the past year. Individuals have the chance of repelling the spell if they pass a MR with a Difficulty of 80.</string>
    <string name = "telemetryEff">+5 to MR Difficulty and an additional year</string>

    <string name = "magnetControl">Magnetic Control</string>
    <string name = "magnetControlDesc">This spell grants control over the surrounding magnetic fields in a 25-meter radius, allowing the caster to freely move any metallic body with a force equivalent to Strength 13. Magnetism control is such that actions are executed as an automatic effect on metal. For instance, a character using this spell could paralyze someone on a full armor, or snatch the sword out of his hands. In these cases, it is not possible to avoid such effects by passing an Opposed Strength or Agility Check. This control is an active action, therefore the caster must have the action in order to perform it, and consequently this cannot be used as a defense. Against objects or creatures only partially composed of metals, or those that are Energy shielded, the control is reduced to Strength 8.</string>
    <string name = "magnetControlEff">+25 meters to radius</string>

    <string name = "forge">Forge</string>
    <string name = "forgeDesc">This spell employs magic with the purpose of forging objects, using the equivalent of a Forging ability of 100. Since the action is based on supernatural powers, none of the time modifiers in Table 17 apply, and no forging equipment is required. This spell does not produce the material, such as steel, needed for creating specific items; the spellcaster must provide them.</string>
    <string name = "forgeEff">+5 to Forging ability</string>

    <string name = "solidBody">Solid Body</string>
    <string name = "solidBodyDesc">The targeted body becomes immensely solid with stone-like resistance. When cast upon individuals, they receive a natural AT of 6 against non-Energy Attacks and a Damage Barrier of 100. The character\'s muscles strengthen for as long as he remains in this state, increasing his Strength characteristic by 2 and decreasing his Movement Value by 2. The transformed body resembles a different material depending on the additions employed in the spell; iron, granite, steel, diamonds, etc. The maximum Presence that can be affected is 100.</string>
    <string name = "solidBodyEff">+10 to the maximum Presence affected, +1 to natural AT and +10 to Damage Barrier</string>

    <string name = "resistance">Resistance</string>
    <string name = "resistanceDesc">This spell confers the temporary ability to absorb almost any damage inflicted on an individual. It provides 500 additional Life Points, which allow the targeted individual to use the defense rules of Damage Resistance beings. These extra LP are subtracted before any of the target\'s actual LP. Its Armor Type depends on the character\'s size, as it is described in Chapter 26. The target of this spell cannot use any defense abilities for as long as the spell is maintained. Resistance spells affect only one individual at a time.</string>
    <string name = "resistanceEff">+50 extra LP</string>

    <string name = "petrify">Petrify</string>
    <string name = "petrifyDesc">This spell transforms a physical being into a stone statue. The targeted individual cannot move and has no awareness of the events going on around him for the duration of the spell. This spell can be maintained for years, but the affected being does not age. As soon as the spell ends, the individual returns to his original condition. Any damage or breakage inflicted upon the statue may result in damage, or even death, of the actual character. The target of this spell can resist its affects by passing a MR Check of 120 Difficulty. A subject affected by a Petrify spell is entitled to a reroll after the first day he has been affected, and later, once a week.</string>
    <string name = "petrifyEff">+5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "fissure">Fissure</string>
    <string name = "fissureDesc">This spell causes a violent, but highly concentrated tremor that splits open the earth, creating a fissure 3 meters wide, 10 meters long, and 20 – 50 meters deep. Individuals in the area of the fissure must pass an Agility Check to avoid falling inside and suffering the appropriate impact damage. Constructions in the area of the fissure can also e severely damage, but any structure with a Damage Barrier higher than 40 is not be affected by this spell, since their structure is too dense.</string>
    <string name = "fissureEff">+3 meters long, +1 meter wide, and +5 to Damage Barrier of constructions affected</string>

    <string name = "gravReverse">Reverse Gravity</string>
    <string name = "gravReverseDesc">This spell completely alters gravity in a particular area of the planet, reversing its force. In a way, it turns the world upside down. Everything encompassed within a 25-meter radius immediately starts to "fall" into the sky up to a maximum distance of 50 meters. The caster may set limits on this spell, such as only affecting the interior of a designated structure. Naturally, objects rooted or otherwise fixed to the ground will not fall. Individuals may avoid the effects of the spell by passing a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120. The area of effect remains stationary.</string>
    <string name = "gravReverseEff">+10 meters to radius and height</string>

    <string name = "createMineral">Mineral Creation</string>
    <string name = "createMineralDesc">The spellcaster may use this spell to create anything he wishes, provided it is composed of minerals or metal. The created object cannot have a Presence higher than 40, and it must appear in a logical location according to its nature.</string>
    <string name = "createMineralEff">+5 to the maximum Presence of the created object</string>

    <string name = "terraErudition">Terrain Erudition</string>
    <string name = "terraEruditionDesc">The caster gains immediate and total knowledge of everything in contact with the ground for several kilometers around him. Both constructions and living creatures can be detected straight away, provided they are not immaterial. This spell does not affect energy-sealed places. Terrain Erudition covers a 400-meter radius around the caster.</string>
    <string name = "terraEruditionEff">+200 meters to radius</string>

    <string name = "earthquake">Earthquake</string>
    <string name = "earthquakeDesc">This spell causes a devastating tremor in a 500-meter radius with enough potential force to destroy a city. Any construction with a Damage Barrier lower than 40 is to be immediately destroyed, while the rest suffer 5 points of damage in the first round; this damage is doubled every subsequent round (10 in the second, 20 in the third, etc). Constructions with a Damage Barrier higher than 150 are not affected by the earthquake at all. All individuals inside the spell zone suffer the appropriate effects from falling debris, depending on their surroundings.</string>
    <string name = "earthquakeEff">+250 meters to radius</string>

    <string name = "gravDestruct">Gravity Destruction</string>
    <string name = "gravDestructDesc">This spell creates a high pressure gravity bubble that can trap any physical entity and damage it to the point it bursts. Trapped creatures must pass a PhR with a Difficulty of 180 every round, or be subject ot damage equal to half the failure level. The victim receives a +5 bonus to the PhR roll for every AT point against Impact. The extreme pressure prevents the target from escaping the area of effect unless it passes an Opposed Check against a Strength of 16. The power of gravity is so strong that even immaterial beings are partially affected by it, although they can apply a +40 bonus to their Resistance Checks and +6 to Strength. The spell affects everything in a 20-meter radius except for the caster. The area of effect remains stationary.</string>
    <string name = "gravDestructEff">+5 meters to radius</string>

    <string name = "createGolem">Create Golem</string>
    <string name = "createGolemDesc">This spell creates a living earthly creature completely under the caster\'s control. This entity is treated as a Being Between Worlds and is subject to the elemental powers and limitations of Earth elementals covered in Chapter 26. The creature has 600 DP, and its maximum level is calculated using the same rules as in the spell Create Being from the Path of Creation.</string>
    <string name = "createGolemEff">+50 DP</string>

    <string name = "incrementGrav">Gravity Increment</string>
    <string name = "incrementGravDesc">The spell increases the atmosphere\'s mass in a particular area, thus augmenting the pull of gravity and with it, the weight of everything contained in the zone. In gaming terms, it automatically doubles the weight of everything in a 500-meter radius.</string>
    <string name = "incrementGravEff">Increase the multiplier by one</string>

    <string name = "meteor">Meteor</string>
    <string name = "meteorDesc">This spell allows the caster to call down a small meteor from the heavens that smashes into the earth with devastating force. Everything within 10 meters of the meteor\'s point of impact suffer a Base Damage of 100 points against the Impact AT, plus an additional 100 points of damage against the Heat AT. Everything 10 – 50 meters from the point of impact suffers the effects of the expansion wave, which immediately hits with the force of a Strength 14 melee attack and inflicts a Base Damage of 60 points. Any point in space the caster can see is considered a valid target for this spell. The meteor takes 1d10+4 rounds to impact after the spell has been cast. Each additional meteor, made possible through the spell\'s Added Effect, strikes 1d10 rounds after the first. The caster can direct each meteor at a different target, but all targets must be designated at the time the spell is cast and cannot later be changed, even if the meteors have not yet impacted.\nThis spell does not take full effect when cast indoors, or in subterranean spaces, so its consequences may be altered depending on the environment.</string>
    <string name = "meteorEff">One additional meteor</string>

    <string name = "controlGrav">Gravity Control</string>
    <string name = "controlGravDesc">This spell grants complete control of all gravitational forces in a particular area of the planet within a 100-kilometer radius of the caster. Inside this area, the spellcaster has absolute dominion of gravity, allowing him to increase or decrease its affects up to ten times its original value, or reverse it. Everything in the area is automatically affected.</string>
    <string name = "controlGravEff">+500 meters to radius</string>

    <string name = "oneWithEarth">One with the Earth</string>
    <string name = "oneWithEarthDesc">The spellcaster merges his essence with the world, obtaining complete control of all mineral and metallic elements in a 100-kilometer radius. This allows him to alter the face of the earth by creating or removing mountains and valleys, redirecting rivers, and so forth. Every stone-based creature within the spell\'s area is required to pass a MR with a Difficulty of 140 in order to avoid being subject to the spellcaster\'s will. Once passed, no rerolls are necessary. The affected parties are entitled to a second roll only when they have altered their base Resistance.</string>
    <string name = "oneWithEarthEff">+100 kilometers to radius and +5 MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "atomicControl">Atomic Control</string>
    <string name = "atomicControlDesc">The caster is able to mold atomic matter in his surroundings like clay. To him, everything that moves is nothing but a set of atoms to manipulate as he wishes. He gains full dominion of all organic and inorganic matter within a 100-meter radius that does not pass a PhR or MR with a Difficulty of 140. There is no limit to what the caster can do with a body or object under his dominion; he may alter its shape and appearance, transform into anything else, or simply scatter its atoms, thereby causing its complete destruction. Since this spell only affects physical matter, it has no effect upon souls or completely immaterial bodies.</string>
    <string name = "atomicControlEff">+5 meters to radius, +5 to MR or PhR Difficulty</string>
</resources>