<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name = "feelDeath">Feel Death</string>
    <string name = "feelDeathDesc">The necromancer automatically detects any death occurring 100 meters around him. This spell also reveals undead creatures if they fail a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120.</string>
    <string name = "feelDeathEff">+25 meters to radius and +5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "seeBeyond">See the Great Beyond</string>
    <string name = "seeBeyondDesc">This spell allows the caster to see specters and other spiritual creatures invisible to the human eye. The caster may bestow this gift upon as many individuals as he wishes, provided the total of their Presences do not exceed 80.</string>
    <string name = "seeBeyondEff">+10 to the maximum Presence affected</string>

    <string name = "controlScavenger">Control Scavengers</string>
    <string name = "controlScavengerDesc">This spell grants the caster control over creatures that feed mostly on the dead. The affected creatures must all be within a 10-meter radius and have a combined Presence less than 20. Some possible examples include vultures, crows, and maggots.</string>
    <string name = "controlScavengerEff">+10 meters to radius</string>

    <string name = "spectralShield">Spectral Shield</string>
    <string name = "spectralShieldDesc">This spell creates a shield of necromantic Energy capable of stopping Spiritual assaults that affect the character\'s supernatural Resistances. The spell does not stop physical attacks. Spectral Shield offers protection against mystical effects, as long as they do not force the character to make a Resistance Check with a Difficulty greater than 140.</string>
    <string name = "spectralShieldEff">+5 to the value of Resistances that can be stopped</string>

    <string name = "drainLife">Drain Life</string>
    <string name = "drainLifeDesc">This spell allows a necromancer to absorb the life force of another living creature, severely injuring the target in the process, while healing himself in turn. The caster must be able to physically touch the target. Any individual affected by this spell is forced to pass a MR Check with a Difficulty of 80 or lose a number of Life Points equal to his Failure Level. The caster then adds this number to his own Life Points, however he cannot exceed his normal maximum. Creatures with Damage Resistance lose five times the amount of their Failure Level, but the caster only receives one-fifth of that number to heal his own wounds. For example, a creature with Damage Resistance that fails its MR Check by 20 points would lose 100 LP, but the caster would only add 20 to his LP total.</string>
    <string name = "drainLifeEff">+5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "necroDetection">Necromantic Detection</string>
    <string name = "necroDetectionDesc">This spell allows the necromancer to detect any living or undead creature within 20 meters of him. Characters who pass a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120 remain undetected by this spell.</string>
    <string name = "necroDetectionEff">+10 meters to radius and +10 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "talkToDead">Talk to the Dead</string>
    <string name = "talkToDeadDesc">This spell allows the necromancer to communicate with dead souls and spirits around him. The spell automatically affects all spirits within 25 meters of the caster that have a Presence less than 40. The caster doesn\'t need to be aware of a spirit\'s exact location.</string>
    <string name = "talkToDeadEff">+10 to the maximum Presence affected</string>

    <string name = "necroParalyze">Necromantic Paralysis</string>
    <string name = "necroParalyzeDesc">This spell freezes the supernatural essence of undead creatures, rendering them unable to move. Any undead being in a 20-meter radius form the caster is automatically subject to Total Paralysis if unable to pass a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120.</string>
    <string name = "necroParalyzeEff">+10 meters to radius and +5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "necromitude">Necromitude</string>
    <string name = "necromitudeDesc">This spell allows an undead creature to recover 50 Life Points. It has no effect upon living beings.</string>
    <string name = "necromitudeEff">+5 Life Points</string>

    <string name = "deathBeam">Death Beam</string>
    <string name = "deathBeamDesc">This spell projects a strong necromantic discharge. The attack hits on the Energy AT and has a Base Damage of 80.</string>
    <string name = "deathBeamEff">+5 to Base Damage</string>

    <string name = "raiseCorpse">Raise Corpses</string>
    <string name = "raiseCorpseDesc">Through necromantic Energy manipulation, the caster can animate corpses and turn them into zombies or skeletons under his control. The dead do not keep the Special Abilities or knowledge they had while alive. But, they maintain their basic abilities - such as those associated with natural weapons and some of their physical Characteristics. The creature\'s Power and Resistances vary according to its body. For instance, a bear\'s cadaver would be considerably more dangerous than that of a human. Basic information on zombies is included in the Bestiary as reference for the GM. A caster can raise a number of corpses equal to 100 Presence points, as long as none of them are individually higher than 20.</string>
    <string name = "raiseCorpseEff">+20 to total number of affected Presences and +5 to their maximum value</string>

    <string name = "deadBody">Dead Body</string>
    <string name = "deadBodyDesc">This spell temporarily stops an individual\'s bodily functions without causing his death. The affected target can still move and act normally and becomes extremely resistant to damage effects and consequences for as long as the spell stays active. Any physical penalty he incurs is reduced by half, and he remains conscious while in the state between life and death. In addition, anyone inspecting the body will be unable to determine its true condition. The maximum total of Presences affected by this spell cannot exceed 40.</string>
    <string name = "deadBodyEff">+5 to the maximum Presence affected</string>

    <string name = "drainMag">Drain Magic</string>
    <string name = "drainMagDesc">This spell drains the magical energy out of an individual or an object and transfers it to the necromancer. Any individual affected by this spell is forced to pass a MR Check with a Difficulty of 100 or lose a number of Zeon points equal to twice the number by which he failed the check. The caster immediately absorbs this Zeon.</string>
    <string name = "drainMagEff">+5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "destroyUndead">Destroy the Undead</string>
    <string name = "destroyUndeadDesc">This spell completely destroys the essence of the undead. Any necromantic entity targeted by this spell is forced to pass a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120 or suffer damage equivalent to twice the number by which he failed the check. Creatures with Damage Resistance increase this amount by their Damage Resistance multiple.</string>
    <string name = "destroyUndeadEff">+5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "drainChar">Drain Characteristic</string>
    <string name = "drainCharDesc">By touching a living creature, the necromancer can absorb one of the individual\'s Characteristics, increasing his own in the process. The necromancer must decide the Characteristic that he will drain before executing the spell. The designated target loses 1 point from that Characteristic for every 10 points by which he fails the 120 Difficulty MR Check. If the natural value of the victim\'s drained Characteristic is higher than that of the necromancer\'s, the necromancer adds that drained point to his own Characteristic. If the target\'s Characteristic is lower, the necromancer needs to absorb 3 Characteristic points to increase his own by 1. The increased attributes remain for as long as the spell is maintained. Lost Characteristics are recovered at a rate of 1 per hour once the caster cancels the spell.</string>
    <string name = "drainCharEff">+5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "controlDead">Control the Dead</string>
    <string name = "controlDeadDesc">The necromancer obtains absolute control of any undead creature in a 20-meter radius. Dominion over the undead stays active for as long as the spell is maintained, but it does not affect other necromantic creatures that might approach the area later. The undead can attempt to avoid being controlled by passing a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120. They will only be allowed to reroll upon receiving an order completely contradictory to their nature; therefore creatures without a will, such as animated corpses, can never be freed.</string>
    <string name = "controlDeadEff">+10 meters to radius and +5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "witherLife">Wither Life</string>
    <string name = "witherLifeDesc">This spell creates a necromantic Energy area that immediately kills any inferior life form - such as small animals and plants - around the caster. Any living being with a Presence less than 20 that is within 10 meters from the caster automatically rots away.</string>
    <string name = "witherLifeEff">+5 meters to radius</string>

    <string name = "necroShield">Necromantic Shield</string>
    <string name = "necroShieldDesc">This spell creates an Energy shield from the essence of dead souls that protects against all kinds of attacks. The shield can absorb up to 1000 points of damage before breaking.</string>
    <string name = "necroShieldEff">+100 Resistance Points</string>

    <string name = "dominateLife">Dominate Life</string>
    <string name = "dominateLifeDesc">This spell allows the caster to enslave a living being\'s soul. The targeted victim can resist the spell if he passes a MR Check with a Difficulty of 100. The controlled individual receives a new check each day, and he also receives the chance to make another MR Check every time he receives an order completely against his behavior.</string>
    <string name = "dominateLifeEff">+5 to MR Target Number Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "vampireStigma">Vampire Stigma</string>
    <string name = "vampireStigmaDesc">The target of this spell automatically absorbs 10%% of the damage he deals to any opponent. Vampire Stigma will work both on physical attacks and direct damage spells, as well as similar supernatural powers. Attacks against creatures with Damage Resistance give the caster only 2%% of the dealt damage.</string>
    <string name = "vampireStigmaEff">+5%% additional damage absorption (+1%% against creatures with Damage Resistance)</string>

    <string name = "spectralForm">Spectral Form</string>
    <string name = "spectralFormDesc">The necromancer\'s physical body becomes a burning, spectral mass that damages the essence of all living beings that comes into contact with it. Anyone touching its body feels the chill of death and is forced to make a PhR or MR Check with a Difficulty equal to twice the necromancer\'s Presence. If the affected character fails the check, he suffers an All Action Penalty and loses a number of Life Points equal to half the number by which he failed the check. The necromancer can only be hit by Energy damaging attacks for as long as he remains in this condition. The maximum Presence affected by this spell is 100.</string>
    <string name = "spectralFormEff">+5 to the maximum Presence affected</string>

    <string name = "necroMod">Necromantic Modification</string>
    <string name = "necroModDesc">This spell can target either a living or undead entity, temporarily granting it new Powers and Abilities. If the target is an undead creature, it receives 100 additional DP to obtain any of the Special Powers detailed in Chapter 26, as a creature with a Gnosis of 25 would. When directed at a living being, the DP granted by the spell are reduced by half. The effects of this spell do not overlap, and subjects may be affected by it only once.</string>
    <string name = "necroModEff">+10 DP</string>

    <string name = "deadSummon">Summon the Dead</string>
    <string name = "deadSummonDesc">This spell calls the souls of dead people or specters to the necromancer. The caster is able to summon spirits selectively, although some other soul may present itself if the specific one he is seeking to contact is unavailable. Summon the Dead only works on spirits still tied to the world, or on spectral creatures, but not upon souls already transmigrated to the Flow of Souls. The maximum total of Presence affected cannot exceed 50.</string>
    <string name = "deadSummonEff">+5 to the maximum Presence affected</string>

    <string name = "raiseSpecters">Raise Specters</string>
    <string name = "raiseSpectersDesc">By dominating the souls of the dead, the necromancer can pervert their essences and turn them into specters at his service. These ghosts keep a small part of the capacities they used to have in life, but they lose the majority of their old powers and attributes in the process. A specter raised by this spell reduces to half (and round up) the Level achieved in life. However, it abides by the general rules of undead spirits and receives 100 extra DP which the caster employs to provide it with the powers he sees fit (as a Gnosis 20 being). The spell will only work on recently deceased souls still waiting for the Calling. It can raise up to 100 Presence points among several spirits, provided none of them is higher than 30.</string>
    <string name = "raiseSpectersEff">+20 to the number of Presences and +5 to their maximum value</string>

    <string name = "drainLifeForce">Drain Life Force</string>
    <string name = "drainLifeForceDesc">This spell absorbs an individual\'s vital force and transmits it to whoever the necromancer designates. The target must pass a MR Check with a Difficulty of 100 or lose 1 Constitution and 1 Power Point for every 10 points by which he fails the check. The affected individual also ages gradually, according to his Failure Level. Absorbed points allow the necromancer (or the subject absorbing them) to rejuvenate and recover part of his lost vitality, up to starting levels. Characters deprived of their vital force can never recover it, except through supernatural abilities that make it possible.</string>
    <string name = "drainLifeForceEff">+5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "kill">Kill</string>
    <string name = "killDesc">This spell stops a subject\'s bodily functions causing immediate death. It only works on living beings and is useless against spirits and some inanimate Beings Between Worlds. The affected character must pass a MR or PhR Check with a Difficulty of 80 to survive.</string>
    <string name = "killEff">+5 to MR or PhR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "soulBeam">Soul Beam</string>
    <string name = "soulBeamDesc">This spell projects a magical Energy discharge composed of withered souls. The spell hits on the Energy AT and has a 100 point Base Damage. It only affects beings with a soul; lifeless physical bodies, such as walls or golems, are ignored. Given the nature of the discharge, only those with the capacity of seeing spirits are able to sense it.</string>
    <string name = "soulBeamEff">+5 to Base Damage</string>

    <string name = "necroChimera">Necromantic Chimera</string>
    <string name = "necroChimeraDesc">This spell creates an undead creature subject to the caster\'s control. This entity is developed as a Being Between Worlds with 600 DP and a Gnosis of 25. However, the necromancer cannot create the entity from scratch; in order to develop it, he must gather pieces from several corpses. If looking to endow any power or essential ability, he must first find the bodies of beings that possessed those powers. For instance, if wanting to confer Natural Flight, he must find the corpse of a creature who had that specific ability in life. The existence of the chimera is directly linked to the necromancer\'s soul. Therefore, its maximum level is calculated using the same rules as in the spell Create Being of the path of Creation.</string>
    <string name = "necroChimeraEff">+50 DP</string>

    <string name = "lifePerversion">Life Perversion</string>
    <string name = "lifePerversionDesc">This spell corrupts the essence of a living being and stops its bodily functions, immediately transforming it into an undead entity. The affected character maintains the same Characteristics and abilities he had in life - although his animated corpse status will naturally grant him the advantage of Physical Exemption. Individuals may avoid transformation by passing a MR Check with a Difficulty of 100.</string>
    <string name = "lifePerversionEff">+5 to MR or PhR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "vassalage">Vassalage</string>
    <string name = "vassalageDesc">This spell permanently ties an undead creature\'s soul to that of the necromancer. Thus, the spellcaster automatically becomes its hierarchical superior, and the monster\'s existence depends upon him. Although this spell does not endow the necromancer with real control upon the creature, their lives are tied together in a manner such that if the master is destroyed, the creature will perish too. The affected undead may resist Vassalage by passing a MR or PhR Check with a Difficulty of 80.</string>
    <string name = "vassalageEff">+5 to MR or PhR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "drainSouls">Drain Souls</string>
    <string name = "drainSoulsDesc">This spell allows the necromancer to snatch another individual\'s soul so he may feed on its essence and power. The stronger the absorbed spirit, the greater the energy received. The targeted individual must pass a MR Check with a Difficulty of 120 or lose an amount of Presence equal to half the number by which he failed the check. For every 5 Presence points lost, the target loses 1 level and all the capacities or powers dependent upon it (with the exception of knowledge-based abilities). If the target\'s Presence ever reaches zero, its soul is considered to be completely extinguished and he dies. For every 10 points of Presence absorbed, the necromancer temporarily increases one of his Characteristics by 1, or he can choose to receive 10 DP to acquire any Power or Essential creature ability. These increased Characteristic values will vanish at the rate of one per day, and DP will decrease at a rate of 20 per day.</string>
    <string name = "drainSoulsEff">+5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "surpassDeath">Surpass Death</string>
    <string name = "surpassDeathDesc">This spell allows a living person to defeat death. The target becomes an undead entity without ties and can therefore exist in the world on his own power. The spell must be cast at the exact moment of the person\'s death - or a few seconds before (it will not cause death by itself). The caster is free to decide if the target in question becomes a Being Between Worlds or a Spirit, but in any case it will have a Gnosis of 25. The spell confers 150 extra DP to use for any of the essential abilities or powers described in Chapter 26. If the caster chooses for the target to become a Spirit, the target must spend 100 DP to that end. He can also choose up to 50 DP in Disadvantages and Penalties, which will give him extra points. Excess DP increases the level as described in the spell Chimera. Surpass Death will only work on living creatures at the moment of death; therefore, it will have no effect upon creatures of a necromantic nature.</string>
    <string name = "surpassDeathEff">+10 DP and +5 optional DP in Disadvantages</string>

    <string name = "trueRise">True Rise</string>
    <string name = "trueRiseDesc">This spell raises a corpse allowing it to maintain its knowledge and every one of the powers and abilities it had in life. Unfortunately, the raised creature becomes an undead being lacking true soul. The spell affects deceased characters or creatures with a Presence score less than 30 whose bodies are at the reach of the caster. If death occurred a long time before the spell is cast, the raised creature\'s physical abilities might be damaged. Characters resurrected once through this spell cannot be resurrected again. Keep in mind that, even though the character is an undead entity, it is not under the control of the necromancer.</string>
    <string name = "trueRiseEff">+5 to the maximum Presence affected</string>

    <string name = "lifeWell">Well of Life</string>
    <string name = "lifeWellDesc">This spell creates a field of dark Energy centered on the necromancer that allows him to absorb half the Life Points lost by all living beings within 50 meters of him. These Life Points go towards healing any sort of wounds he may have suffered. Well of Life itself does not inflict damage, but necromancers usually combine its effects with other damaging magics at their disposal.</string>
    <string name = "lifeWellEff">+50 meters to radius</string>

    <string name = "cursedLand">Cursed Land</string>
    <string name = "cursedLandDesc">The caster corrupts a small fragment of the world, haunting a section of land. Inside this area, all deceased individuals are instantaneously resurrected as undead creatures subject to his control. Deceased characters automatically become animated corpses, but one out of a hundred are resurrected as a specter. These undead creatures only act inside the cursed land (see Level 28 and Level 60 spells of this Path as a reference). The magic sustaining them will vanish if they leave the area. The spell haunts a one-kilometer radius, stationary to the place where it was cast.</string>
    <string name = "cursedLandEff">+1 kilometer to radius</string>

    <string name = "sustenance">Sustenance</string>
    <string name = "sustenanceDesc">This spell affects the essence of one or several undead creatures maintained by the spell, allowing for their existence even after the necromancer stops paying for their maintenance. For instance, if the spellcaster uses Sustenance upon a zombie animated by the spell Raise Corpses, the creature will continue to stay active once that spell has ended. The caster may affect as many individuals as he may wish, provided the total of their Presences is not higher than 60.</string>
    <string name = "sustenanceEff">+10 to the maximum Presence affected</string>

    <string name = "rawMaterial">Raw Material</string>
    <string name = "rawMaterialDesc">This spell generates the corrupt energy used by necromantic magic to resurrect corpses and spirits, enabling the caster to create the raw material necessary to resurrect corpses at a later stage. The spell forms necromantic material, equivalent to a thousand human bodies, or a smaller amount of other more powerful creatures instead.</string>
    <string name = "rawMaterialEff">+1000 additional bodies</string>

    <string name = "deadLord">Lord of the Dead</string>
    <string name = "deadLordDesc">The Lord of the Dead extends its presence in the world, subduing all undead creatures in a 100-kilometer radius. All creatures within the spell area are subjected to the spellcaster\'s control unless they pass a MR Check with a Difficulty of 140. Once they do, no rerolls are necessary. Affected individuals are not entitled to a new check unless they alter their Resistances.</string>
    <string name = "deadLordEff">+100 kilometers to radius and +5 to MR Difficulty</string>

    <string name = "comeBackFromDead">Come Back from the Dead</string>
    <string name = "comeBackFromDeadDesc">This spell returns a deceased creature\'s spirit to the world, even after it has gone back to the Flow of Souls or has been scattered. The character returns as an undead being, with his soul and essence untouched. If the body of the deceased character still exists, it will come back to it. If it does not, he may reincarnate in a new one or become an immaterial specter. As is the case in similar spells, the time elapsed between death and resurrection is a restraining factor to the efficacy of the spell. Resuscitated souls cannot have a base Presence higher than 30, and the elapsed time since death cannot exceed one month. Destroyed or resurrected souls cannot be affected by this spell.</string>
    <string name = "comeBackFromDeadEff">+5 to the maximum Presence affected and twice the time elapsed since the subject\'s death</string>

    <string name = "awakening">The Awakening</string>
    <string name = "awakeningDesc">The Awakening is the most powerful of necromantic spells. By corrupting a part of the world, the caster extends his shadow over all existence and brings back the dead, subjugating them to his full control. The Awakening is not limited to a normal area of effect; all deceased persons in the world with a Presence lower than 50 are affected. In case spirits are still awaiting the calling they are raised either as specters or animated corpses. A small percentage of the deceased - one out of every ten thousand - come back with full faculties.</string>
    <string name = "awakeningEff">+5 to the maximum Presence affected</string>
</resources>